Countries collection, 1540-2006 (bulk 1920-1970)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Great Britain [see England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales]
  - Guyana
    - Women's organizations
      - The Children's Alma Mater, 1960-61 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - The Children's Dorcas Club, 1958-67 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Women's Advisory Committee in the free trade union movement, 1965-66 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Women's League of Social Service, 1959-65 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Germany
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1817-1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Stöcker, Helene
        - General, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - Writings, 1915-44 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1896-1951 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - Lin Stearns to Helen Mandlebaum re life in post-World War I Germany, 1922-23 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Grethe to "Onkel Paul" (in German), describing deplorable conditions in northern Germany, 1924-25 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - General, 1922-35 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Der Internationale Kongress für Frauenwerke und Frauenbestrebungen, Berlin, Sep 1896: proceedings (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Report on German Project: Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Publications
      - General, 1905-85 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
      - Ausblick vom Münsterturm by Elle Heuss-Knapp, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Das deutsche Landfrauenbuch by Anne Marie Koeppen, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - The Feminist Movement in Germany 1894-1933 by Evans, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Die Frau der Gegenwart, 15 Mar 1913 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Die Frau ist frei geboren: Texte zur Frauenemanzipation, Vol 21870-1918, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Frauen in Dresden: Dokumente, Geschichten, Porträts, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Mit Mut und Phantasie: Frauen suchen ihre verlorene Geschichte, eine Documentation, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Women's Organizations: National Council of Women, 1948-68 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Haiti
    - Biographical materials: Comhaire-Sylvain, Suzanne, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1949-58 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - General, 1951-57, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Women's Organizations
      - Comision Interamericana de Mujeres: Resumen del Estudio sobre la condicion de la Mujer Trabajadora, Haiti, May 1957 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Ligue Féminine d'Action Sociale, 1948-57, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Honduras
    - Clippings, 1946-67 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - General, 1947-51 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Women's Organizations: Comision Interamericana de Mujeres, Seccion de Honduras, 1947-69, undated (Box 20, Folder 8-12)
  - Hong Kong, 1957-63 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Hungary
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1925-50 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Bobula, Ida, 1933-60 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Kéthly, Anna, 1940-57 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1913-70, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - General, 1951-56, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Publications
      - The Hungarian Woman, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Nők Lapja, Women's International Democratic Federation, Hungary, 1950-51 (Box 20, Folder 20-22)
      - Nőmunkás (Woman Worker) Supplement, Jun 1913 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Women's Organizations, 1937-68, undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - ==Iceland, 1895-1961, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - India
    - Biographical materials
      - Alva, Violet, 1958-59 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Amrit Kaur, Rajkumari, 1935-64, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Chakko, Sarah, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Chandy, (Judge) Anna, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Cousins, Margaret E., circa 1955 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Gandhi, Indira, 1956-78, undated (Box 21, Folder 6-8)
      - Kripalani, Sucheta, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Mehta, Hansa, 1954-56 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Menon, Lakshmi, 1953-77, undated (Box 21, Folder 11-14)
      - Naidu, Sarojini, 1926-49, undated (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
      - Nehru, Rameshwari: Gandhi is my Star, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi, 1938-77 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Ramabai, Sarasvati, 1922-23(?), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Rangarao, K. Shanthi, 1959-63, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Reddy, Dr. S. Muthulakshmi, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - Sarkar, Indira, 1947-49 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - Sorabji, Cornelia, 1930, 1954, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Tata, Dorab, 1928, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956-57, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Clippings
      - 1887-1929 (Box 21, Folder 26-28)
      - 1930-71, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Conferences and Reports
      - All India Women's Conference
        - General, 1927-64, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - Second Session, Delhi, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 6)
        - Fourth, Bombay, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 7)
        - Fifth Session, Lahore, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 8)
        - Eleventh Session, Ahmedabad, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 9)
        - Twelfth Session, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - Thirteenth Session, Delhi, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 11)
        - Twenty-first Session, Gwalior, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 12)
        - Twenty-second Session, Bangalore, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - Twenty-fourth Session, Phaltan, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 14)
        - Twenty-sixth Session, Indore, 19567 (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - Reports and essays, 1962-64 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Anti-Purdah Convention, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Adult Education, 1959-66, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-62 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Legal Status of Women
      - Memoranda on the Constitution, 1930-33 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Devadasi Abolition Bill, 1931, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Hindu Code Bill 1951; Hindu Marriage Bill 1954; Hindu Marriage Act 1955 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Indian Divorce Act 1869 and amendments, 1910-29, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Statements and essays by women's organizations, 1931-33 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Women's Right to Property, 1937, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "Women's Rights Under Hindu the Law" report of the Committee Appointed by the Government of H.H. the Maharaja of Mysore, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Publications
      - General, 1918-60 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - "The Awakening of Indian Women" by Kamaladevi Chattopadhyayya and others, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Indian Industries and Labour Bulletin, 1923-30 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - "Industrial Training for Women: The Value of Cottage Industries," Department of Industries, Panjab, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - "Women in Indian Industries" by Padmini Sengupta, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - The Calcuttan, This Issue: Mostly About Women, Sep 1967 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1931-62, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - All Bengal Women's Union, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Family Planning Association of India, 1961-68 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - National Council of Women's Education, 1963-64, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - National Council of Women in India
        - General, 1935-61, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
        - Committee on Prison Reform, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Rashtriya Virjanand andh Kanya Vidyalaya Society, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Saheli, undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Young Women's Christian Association, 1919-62 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous, 1961-67, undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Photographs and memorabilia, 1910, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Indonesia
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1921-63, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Long, Lee Hoo, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Poedjoboentero, Soepeni, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Suwano, Nani, 1961, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Tambu, Maryam, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Wahab, Kamsiah, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1955-65 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Conferences and reports
      - Committee of Correspondence Workshop on "Motherschools," 1956 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Kongres Wanita Indonesia, Jul 1963 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Role of Indonesian women, 1957-62, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Report of a Study Tour of the U.S., Aug 1961 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Women's movement in Indonesia, 1966-68, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Publications
      - The Voice of Free Indonesia, Woman and Community issue, 26 Apr 1947 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Indonesia in Brief by Susi S. Prawirawinata, circa 1956 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1958-61, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Perwari, 1960, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Women's International Club, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous: photo postcard of woman and child, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Iran
    - Biographical materials
      - Afrouz, Novin, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Diba, Empress Farah, 1971-75 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Kazimi, Kechkinnen, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Manouchéhrian, Mehrangiz, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Pahlavi, Princess Ashraf, 1970-74 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Rahbari, Ghosi, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Samii, Nayereh, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Clippings, 1920-68, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 26-28)
    - Conferences and reports
      - Children and education, 1964, undated (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - Status of women, 1954-64 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1957-68, undated (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - High Council of Women's Associations of Iran, 1962-66, undated (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - International Women's Club, 1964-68, undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - Iranian Federation of Women Lawyers, 1961, undated (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - Jewish Ladies' Organization of Iran, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - Rah-e-Now Association, 1955-61, undated (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - Soraya Clubs (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - The Women's Organisation of Iran
        - The Employment of Women in the Higher Echelons of the Public and Private Sectors, Dec 1975 (Box 24, Folder 38)
        - The Iranian Woman Past and Present (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Iraq (Sumeria)
    - General, 1948-87 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "Sumerian Affiliations: A Plea for Reconsideration" by Ida Bobula, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Iraqi Women's League, circa 1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Ireland
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1925-60, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Devlin, Bernadette, 1970-75, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - de Markievicz, Constance, 1922-72 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Whittaker, Ismena: A Tribute to the Memory of Ismena Whittaker; of Sligo, Ireland, dedicated to her relatives and Friends by Hannah Doyle, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1920-76, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Publications
      - Letters of a Young Irishwoman to Her Sister, 1878 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Out for Ourselves: The Lives of Irish Lesbians and Gay Men, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Women's Organizations
      - Irish Countrywomen's Association, 1961, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Irish Housewives Association, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Women's Social and Progressive League, 1938-39 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Women's Unionist Associations, 1893 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Israel
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1931-73 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Golda Meir, 1956-69 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1971-76, undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Conferences and reports: International Seminar on Participation of Women in Social and Educational Development, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - General, 1950-76, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Publications: "The Stranger Within Thy Gates" by Alice Campbell Klein, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Women's Organizations
      - Council of Women's Organizations in Israel, 1903, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Women for a Free Society, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Women's International Zionist Organisation, 1962-67 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Working Women's Council, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Italy
    - Biographical materials, 1926-59, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1921-73, undated (Box 26, Folder 8-10)
    - General, 1938-66, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Publications [see also Oversize]
      - Al Femminile testimonianze femministe, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Compagna, Anno I, numero 1 Jan 1972 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - donne e politica, #14, 17, 1972-73 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Nuova dwf: donnawomanfemme, 3 Apr-Jun 1977 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Notiziario Trimestrale, Consiglio Nazionale delle Donne Italiane, Oct 1967 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Partigiane della Liberta', 1973 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Socialismo e Questione Femminile in Italia, 1892-1922 by Franca Pieroni Bortolotti (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - La Vie Femminile, Anno V, numero 5 Apr 1972 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Women of Rome by Alberto Moravia and Sam Waagenaar, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1927, 1961-66, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Centro di Studi Storici sul movimento di liberazione della donna in Italia, 1981-82 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Centro Italiano Femminile, 1955-66 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Unione Donne Italiane, 1966-73 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
  - Ivory Coast, 1962-66, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Jamaica, [see also: Trinidad, Tobago, and Jamaica]1930, 1966-68
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1930, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Jamaica Federation of Women, 1965-66, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Japan [see also Oversize materials]
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1919-71, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Kiyo Harano Chujo, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Uta Hayashi, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Teru Mogi, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Shio Sakanishi, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Tsugi Shiraishi, 1960-65, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Michiko Shoda (Empress of Japan), 1958-58 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Kaji Yajima, 1916-25, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Clippings
      - In English, 1890s-1970s, undated (Box 28, Folder 9-16)
      - In Japanese (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Conferences and reports
      - Miscellaneous, 1954-66 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Publications Analyses, General Headquarters, Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, 1946-52 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Regional Symposium for Women in Hokuriku, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Survey Report on the Problems of Women's Higher Education, Occupation and Home, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Tokyo Symposium on Women, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - General
      - General, 1947-66, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - "Encyclopedia of Woman's History in Japan" by "a committee of research scholars under the direction of Baroness Ishimoto, 1935 to 1939": typescript
        - Contents, Parts 1, 2, and 3 (Box 28, Folder 24-28)
        - Part 4 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
      - Geishas, 1923-30 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Hinamatsuri dolls, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Images of women, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - "A Short History of Japanese Women" by Akiyama Yoko, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Stickers and postcards, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Publications
      - General, 1935-76 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Bijin-ga II-Japanese Feminine Beauty, plates selected from Feminine Beauty in Japanese Painting published by Toto Bunka Co., Ltd., Tokyo, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - The Changing Social Position of Women in Japan by Takashi Koyama, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - The Force of Women in Japanese History [in Japanese] by Mary R. Beard (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - The Feminist Japan, Feminist International No. 2, 1980 (Box 29)
      - The Japanese Woman: A Pictorial, Japan Travel Bureau, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - The Japanese Woman Looking Forward by H. v.Straehlen, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Japanese Women, the Japanese Woman's Commission for the World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Japanese Women, Research Institute on Women's Problems, 1957-71 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Nisseijo (The Song of Sun and Stars) by Frances Hawks Cameron Burnett, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Pioneer Women Educators of Japan: 24 Leaders of the Century, The Japanese Association of University Women, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Social Education in Japan 1965, Ministry of Education (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Women of Japan by Christine Arnothy, photographs by Marc Riboud, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Women of the Meiji Era by Maude Whitmore Madden, 1919 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Women Workers (in Japanese), 1963 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Women's organizations
      - General, 1954-73, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - List of Women's National Organizations as of July 1958 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Catalogue of Japanese Women's Organizations, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Committee of Correspondence, 1960-62 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Federation of Japanese Women's Organizations, circa 1954 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Institute for Women's Culture, Ochanomizu University: library catalogues #2, 3, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Kobe Women's Evangelistic School, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Osaka Municipal Women's Education Center, 1959, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Women's and Minor's Bureau, Ministry of Labor
        - General, 1952-54, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - Bulletins and "Facts," 1952-53 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        - "The Basic Stratum of Japan: a woman's life in a farm village in the San-in area" by Yasuko Mizoue, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - "Japanese Women Today," Oct 1964 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Statistical Materials Relating to Japanese Women, 1951, 1953-54, 1964-65 (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - The Status of Women in Japan, 1962, 1968, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Status of Japanese Women Workers/Women Workers in Japan, 1955, 1964, 1967-68 (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - "Women's Week in Japan," 1961-68 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - YWCA of Japan, 1936, 1963-66 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Jordan
    - General, 1962-78, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Women's Organizations, 1948-64, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Kenya
    - Biographical materials, 1959, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1930s-70s (Box 32, Folder 2-5)
    - Kenya Women's Seminar/East Africa Women's Seminar, 1962-64 (Box 32, Folder 6-8)
    - Publications
      - Kenya Women Look Ahead by Celina Oloo and Virginia Cone, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Women in Kenya, Journal of the East Africa Women's League, March Quarter, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Women's organizations
      - General, 1960-67, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - East Africa Women's League, 1953-60, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - Kenya Women's Association, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Kenya Women's Society, 1962-64 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Maendelo Ya Wanawake Organisation, 1959-68, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - National Christian Council of Kenya, Home Industries Scheme, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - YWCA of Kenya, 1961-62, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Korea
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1924-77, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Chung-il Choo, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Helen Kim, 1958-61 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Soonkee Lee, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Tai Young Lee, 1977, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1920s, 1940s-70s (Box 33, Folder 6-8)
    - Conferences and reports: "An Essay on Current Situations and Problems of Korean Women" by Choong Yang Choung 1960; "Report on Fouth U.N. Seminar" by Choong Ryan Chung, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Publications
      - The Korean Information Bulletin, 1950-55 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - My Forty Year Fight for Korea by Louise Yim, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Women's organizations: YWCA of Korea, 1968-69 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Laos, 1961, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Lebanon
    - Biographical materials, 1959, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Clippings
      - In English, 1946-57 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - In Arabic (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - General, 1959-62, undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Women's Organizations
      - General, 1958-59, undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Beirut College for Women, 1967, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Lebanese Union for Child Welfare, undated (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Palestinian Arab Women League, 1957-61, undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Village Welfare Society, 1961, undated (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Young Women's Christian Association of Beirut, 1949-62 (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Young Women's Muslim Association, undated (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Lesotho [see Basutoland] (Box 33)
  - Liberia
    - Biographical materials: Sarah Clarisse Simpson George, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Clippings, 1959-71 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Conferences and reports
      - First Regional West African Women's Talks report by Liberian delegates, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - Report of the National Teachers Association of Liberia, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Publications
      - "Strictly for the Ladies: Liberian Recipes Tested and Given From the Kitchen of Eugenia Simpson Cooper," 1957 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Women's organizations
      - General, 1958-59 (Box 33, Folder 30)
      - Federation of Liberian Business Women, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Libya
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Women's organizations, 1961-65, undated (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Liechtenstein, 1970-71, undated (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Luxembourg, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Madagascar (and Malagasy Republic), 1962-64 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Malawi (formerly known as Nyasaland), 1923, 1959-61 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Malaysia
    - General, 1958-63 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Women's organizations
      - General, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - AWAM, All Women's Action Society, circa 1988 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Malayan Women Teacher's Union, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - National Association of Women's Institutes Federation of Malaya, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Young Women's Christian Association, 1961-68 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Maldive Islands, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Mali, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Mauritius, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Mexico
    - Biographical materials
      - General, 1951, 1966, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Gloria Salas de Calderone, 1963, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1856-1977, undated (Box 34, Folder 13-16)
    - International Women's Day March in San Crostobal de Las Casas, Chiapas, Mexico: photographs by Will Ouimet, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Publications
      - General, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 18)
      - Boletin Documental sobre Las Mujeres, Vol III, No. 1 1972 (Box 34, Folder 19)
      - Brecha: Un periódico realizado por mujeres, 1963-64 (Box 34, Folder 20)
      - Mujer Cetemista, Feb 1963 (Box 34, Folder 21)
      - La Situación Jurídica de la Mujer Miexicana, Alianza de Mujeres de Mexico, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 22)
      - Women's Reproductive Rights in Mexico: A Shadow Report, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Women's organizations
      - Universidad Femenina de Mexico, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 24)
      - Women's Political Ideary, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 25)
      - Zapoteca-Chinateca Assembly Commission of Relations, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Morocco
    - Biographical materials, 1959, undated (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Clippings, 1955-70, undated (Box 34, Folder 28-29)
    - General, 1958-63 (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Publications
      - Petit Guide de la Jeune Mère, in French and Arabic, undated (Box 34, Folder 31)
      - Yacout: miroir de la femme Marocaine, Mar 1966 (Box 34, Folder 32)